### Contact

8582545195 (Mobile) silyus@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/salimgrant (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Game Development System Design Production

# Salim Grant

# Senior Designer

San Mateo, California, United States

# Summary

Senior designer with experience in online game development and project management. Well versed in free to play subscription systems, system creation, and content creation. Management experience with teams in excess of 20 members. My goal is to design fun, innovative, and emergent video game experiences while learning new things along the way.

### Experienced in:

- Systems Design
- Content Design
- · Boss Design
- Dungeon Design
- Level Design
- Al design
- Combat Design
- Class Design
- Itemization
- Progression Systems
- Free-to-Play
- Project Planning
- Management of multiple disciplines
- VR Development
- Unity Development
- Basic C++/# knowledge

# Experience

Wonderstorm

Senior Combat Designer

May 2022 - December 2023 (1 year 8 months)

Wonderstorm is a double-threat multimedia startup dedicated to creating timeless entertainment franchises anchored by rich, character-driven stories and engaging video games that will delight audiences of all ages for

generations. We're currently developing The Dragon Prince, a Netflix animated series and a deep, engaging video game – both from the same world and vision.

Cryptic Studios
Senior Designer
July 2017 - May 2022 (4 years 11 months)
Los Gatos, California

As senior game designer I wear many hats while a member of the Neverwinter design team. From concept to implementation, I create full features including itemization, boss and enemy design, quest creation, and progression systems. I have also refactored core game systems, and internal tool data structures to be easier to use. Other responsibilities include creation of modular data making reuse or expansion of features easier to manage and mentoring and onboarding new designers when they join the team.

### Responsibilities:

- · Level layout and design
- Gameplay balance and tuning
- Story
- Direction of visual look and feel
- UI design
- · System design

#### Accomplishments Include:

- Designed and implemented high visibility quests, boss encounters, game systems, and general content
- Restructured enemy data flow for ease of tuning and modifying
- Creation of new experimental and unique gameplay for Neverwinter
- Mentoring of new designers
- Creation of new and management of all existing events
- Implementation of new combat class

### Modules worked on

- · Lost City of Omu
- Ravenloft
- The Heart of Fire
- Undermountain
- Uprising
- Infernal Descent

- Rage of Bel
- Avernus
- Sharandar
- · Jewel of the North
- Dragonbone Vale

#### Rank17

Lead Game Designer September 2016 - May 2017 (9 months)

Greater San Diego Area

September 2016 - May 2017

As lead designer I oversaw the creation of our game titles. From initial concept and design to implementation and release I was responsible for creating and implementing several aspects of each game while tackling the challenges of developing on the VR platform.

### Responsibilities:

- · Level layout and design
- Gameplay balance and tuning
- Story
- · Direction of visual look and feel
- UI design
- System design
- · Project scheduling and prioritization

Created concepts, designs, and implemented the following released games:

- · Armed Against the Undead
- Boo Breakers
- Super Pixel Smash
- · Mighty Monster Mayhem

Worked with outsource group overseeing design and implementation of

- BladeShield
- Sniper (Unreleased Title): VR sniper game inspired by silent scope
- Planetary Punchout (Unreleased Title): VR Boxing game inspired by super punch out

Daybreak Game Company LLC Senior Game Designer May 2015 - September 2016 (1 year 5 months)

#### San Diego

#### H1Z1: Just Survive

Overseeing design and implementation of the following:

- Al design and implementation
- Itemization
- Content design and creation
- · Basebuilding design
- New system design and creation

# Cryptic Studios

Staff Designer

January 2015 - May 2015 (5 months)

Los Gatos

Neverwinter: Strongholds

- Managed a small team of systems designers
- Design for guild progression system
- · Structures points system
- Structures growth and buff progression
- · Resource costs and monetization schema

Neverwinter: Elemental Evil

- Companions
- · Class and profession support
- Artifact weapons and enchantment updates

### Sony Online Entertainment

**Creative Director** 

March 2012 - September 2013 (1 year 7 months)

Greater San Diego Area

EQ Next/EQ Next: Landmark

Developed and implemented gameplay systems for a next generation MMO

- Designed the inventory system
- · Created resource schema
- · Designed the reforging system
- · Designed the achievement system

#### Freerealms

Oversaw development of revenue generating systems and defined a path for growth

- Implemented a development system that allowed all disciplines to pitch ideas.
   This resulted in several great features that introduced new mechanics and potential for revenue.
- Worked out a year of releases that introduced more mature MMO elements to the game.
- Designed the adventurer's journal which helped tell a progressive story from the players point of view and helped them keep track of where they were in the story and the various things available to them at that stage in their development
- Designed and implemented event content
- Revamped the marketplace and implemented a \$.99 pricing scheme
- Introduced a cyclical release system to help enhance revenue

#### Vanguard F2P

Prepared game for free-to-play transition and enrichment the gameplay experience for new player acquisition.

- · Assisted in the design of revamped starting areas
- Designed and implemented marketplace schema
- Designed and implemented Lore Stone system rewarding people for exploring out of the way areas
- Re-itemized the world and re-balanced the risk reward metric

# Sony Online Entertainment Senior Game Designer 2007 - 2012 (5 years)

EverQuest II: Age of Discovery

Led mechanics workforce and planned out efficient changes to content and system creation

- Designed and helped implement the beastlord class
- Designed Prestige class level system
- Designed reforging system
- Assisted in the design and oversaw implementation of mercenaries system
- Assisted in the design and implementation of the design your own dungeon system
- Developed stat system that allowed for growth without the need for hard caps

#### EverQuest II: Free-to-Play

Designed and implemented a full re-itemize of the world. Allowing item balance to remain consistent with mechanics changes with minimal internal work.

EverQuest II: Destiny of Velious

Oversaw dungeon development, itemization, and content flow

- Oversaw dungeon design
- Designed and implemented new item system allowing for a larger degree of internal control on items and quicker implementation
- · Designed and implemented loot distribution schema

EverQuest II: Sentinel's Fate

Assisted team in launch of 6th expansion

- Designed and implemented golden path quest series for new players
- Overhaul of the travel system making it easier for player to get to where they needed to go

EverQuest: Underfoot

Assisted team in launch of 16th expansion

- Implemented the achievement system
- Designed and implemented high visibility quests, and general content

Vanguard: Saga of Heroes

Responsible for overseeing all aspects of game development and production.

Assisted in the design and implementation of a level increase and content

Sigil Games Online Senior Game Designer 2004 - 2007 (3 years)

Led small team in conception and implementation of a variety of supplementary systems and content

- Designed and implemented original crafting system
- Oversaw team responsible for implementation and maintenance of system
- Designed harvesting system
- Worked on initial designs of various systems including combat, and classes.
- Designed and implemented high visibility quests, raid encounters and general content
- · Worked on PvP system design

Sony Online Entertainment

3 years

Designer 2003 - 2004 (1 year) Designed and implemented high visibility quests, raids, systems, and content for the following games

- EverQuest: Gates of Discord (PC) Game Designer
- EverQuest: Lost Dungeons of Norrath (PC) Associate Game Designer
- Star Wars Galaxies (PC) Assistant Game Designer

Quality Assurance Analyst 2001 - 2003 (2 years)

# Education

University of Phoenix Computer Software Engineering · (2014 - 2016)

Rancho Bernardo High School (1992 - 1994)

Palomar College Computer Science